A Guide to the Martha Baird Rockefeller papers FA467
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Correspondence, 1; 8.36 Cubic Feet 22 letter document boxes
  - Rockefeller family correspondence, 1.12
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1959-1960; 1967 (Box 18)
      Restricted from access. Material in the Rockefeller family collections that provides the names, correspondence, or activities of living members of the Rockefeller family, and/or documents the net wealth of any Rockefeller family members, is restricted from access.
    - Family Tree, 1959; 1965 (Box 18)
    - Mauze, Abby Rockefeller, 1956-1957; 1960; 1963-1964; 1966 (Box 18)
    - O'Neill, Abby Milton & Family, 1965-1969 (Box 18)
    - Simpson, Marilyn & Family, 1961-1968 (Box 18)
    - Merrill, Grace V. D., 1960-1962 (Box 18)
    - Prentice, Mrs. E. Parmalee, 1952; 1955; 1957; 1960-1962; 1968 (Box 18)
      Friendship with sister of JDR, Jr.; small personal gifts and invitations.
    - Pulling, Mrs. Anna Boice, 1960-1966 (Box 18)
    - Rockefeller Grandchildren, 1959; 1963-1964 (Box 18)
    - Rockefeller, Abby Aldrich, 1948-1949 (Box 18)
      Copy of will; discussions on distribution by JDR, Jr. and children; AAR china distribution.
    - David Rockefeller - Acadia National Park, 1968-1969 (Box 19)
    - David Rockefeller, 1970 (Box 19)
    - David Rockefeller, 1958-1969 (Box 19)
      Exchange of books and photographs; thanks for gift to Center for Inter-American Relations; children's books in library; newspaper clippings; Harvard Divinity Hall; booklet on Acadia.
    - David Rockefeller - Clippings, 1967-1968 (Box 19)
    - JDR Jr. - Copies of creed "I Believe" and 1941 address (Box 19)
    - JDR Jr. - Photographs, "Sculpture of Head", 1964 (Box 19)
    - Clippings and photograph of commemorative plaque, 1962 (Box 19)
    - JDR Jr., 1927-1940 (Box 19)
    - Clippings, 1960 (Box 19)
    - JDR Jr. - Phone booklet, cards, helpful sentiments, 1957-1959 (Box 19)
    - JDR Jr. - Music data re: violin, 1961 (Box 19)
    - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 19)
    - Data on Martha Baird Rockefeller personal history, 1951 (Box 19)
    - JDR Jr. - Organizational memberships, 1953 (Box 19)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 19)
    - JDR Jr. - Memorial service, 1960 (Box 19)
    - JDR Jr. - Biography, 1960-1962 (Box 19)
    - Notes re: Memorial Service, undated, 1960 (Box 19)
    - Portraits, 1956-1962 (Box 19)
    - Portrait for assembly, 1960-1961 (Box 19)
    - JDR Jr. - Time Magazine, 1956 (Box 19)
    - Portrait, Fred Wright, 1961-1966 (Box 19)
    - Private service, 1960 (Box 19)
    - JDR Jr. Memorial Scholarship, 1962-1963 (Box 19)
    - JDR Jr. Memorial Booklets, 1960 (Box 19)
    - Press information - wedding, 1951 (Box 20)
    - Wedding matters, 1951 (Box 20)
    - Tucson - John Goldthorpe, 1960-1965 (Box 20)
    - Tucson - Clippings, 1956-1960 (Box 20)
    - Tucson, 1960 (Box 20)
    - JDR Jr. condolences, 1971 (Box 20)
    - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 20)
    - Riverside Church Memorial Service, 1960 (Box 20)
    - JDR Jr. condolences, A-G, 1960 (Box 20)
    - JDR Jr. condolences, H-P, 1960 (Box 20)
    - JDR Jr. condolences, Q-Z, 1960 (Box 20)
    - JDR Jr. - Press clippings, 1960 (Box 20)
    - Providence, RI correspondence, 1960 (Box 20)
    - Tarrytown, NY correspondence, 1960 (Box 20)
    - JDR Jr. Memorial Booklets, 1960 (Box 21)
    - JDR Jr. condolences-Seal Harbor, 1960 (Box 21)
    - JDR Jr. condolences-Williamsburg, VA, 1960 (Box 21)
    - JDR Jr. tributes, 1960 (Box 21)
    - Dr. Campbell, 1968 (Box 21)
      Restricted from access - personal & confidential.
    - Rockefeller family, JDR 3rd and grandchildren, 1958-1969 (Box 21)
    - Rockefeller family, JDR 3rd and grandchildren, 1958-1965 (Box 21)
    - Rockefeller family, Jay and Sharon, 1967 (Box 21)
    - Rockefeller family, Jay, 1961-1969 (Box 21)
    - Rockefeller family, Laurance S., 1960-1968 (Box 21)
    - Laurance Rockefeller - Clippings and correspondence, 1969 (Box 21)
    - Rockefeller family grandchildren, 1956-1962 (Box 21)
    - NAR wedding clippings, 1963 (Box 21)
    - Rockefeller family, Rodman Clark, 1970 (Box 21)
    - Rockefeller family, NAR children, 1964-1969 (Box 21)
    - Rockefeller family, NAR, 1963-1969 (Box 21)
    - Rockefeller family, NAR, 1964-1968 (Box 21)
    - NAR clippings, 1958 (Box 21)
    - Table linens, 1964 (Box 21)
    - Pocantico Hills church, 1964 (Box 21)
    - Rockefeller family, grandchildren, 1956-1962 (Box 21)
    - Michael C. Rockefeller Memorial Scholarship, 1965 (Box 21)
      Restricted from access.
    - Winthrop Rockefeller family, 1964-1967 (Box 22)
    - Winthrop Rockefeller, 1958-1964 (Box 22)
    - David Fernald - Financial statements, 1969-1970 (Box 22)
    - Office Operations Committee - Rockefeller Plaza, Rockefeller Offices, 1960-1964 (Box 22)
    - Employees' retirement benefits, 1962 (Box 22)
    - Gifts to employees, 1962-1970 (Box 22)
    - Family Christmas lists, 1969-1971 (Box 22)
    - Social secretary, 1969 (Box 22)
    - David Fernald, 1967 (Box 22)
    - Office - Matching Gifts Program, 1970 (Box 22)
    - Martha Baird Rockefeller - Gifts, 1964-1967 (Box 22)
    - Ernst, Joseph W., 1959 (Box 22)
    - Archives - Books, 1959-1962 (Box 22)
    - Gifts, 1967-1969 (Box 22)
    - Gifts to staff, 1961-1965 (Box 22)
    - Gifts - Weddings, family, 1957-1960 (Box 22)
    - Family weddings - Gifts, 1966-1968 (Box 22)
    - Family weddings - News clippings, 1953-1970 (Box 22)
    - Wedding invitations, 1961-1969 (Box 22)
    - Wedding invitations, 1952-1963; binder (Box 22)
  - Political, 1.13
    - Eisenhower - Inauguration, 1956-1957 (Box 22)
      Political contribution; inaugural invitation declined.
    - Winthrop Rockefeller, 1970 (Box 22)
      Contributions to WR campaign.
    - John Lindsay-Elections, 1965; 1969 (Box 22)
    - Mayoral campaign, 1969 (Box 22)
      MBR contributions to Lindsay's campaign.
    - Willkie campaign, 1940 (Box 22)
      MBR wrote words and music of campaign song "We want Wilkie"; copyright papers.
    - Tributes to public figures, 1968-1970 (Box 22)
- Scrapbooks and Photo Albums, 2; 1.41 Cubic Feet 3 legal document boxes
  - MBR Musical Career, 1903-1950 (Box 23)
    Clippings and programs of MBR concerts and social activities.
  - MBR Musical Career, 1931-1950 (Box 24)
  - MBR Personal Photograph Album, 1903-1961 (Box 24)
    Portraits; travel; homes; Red Cross work; Europe.
  - Photograph Album - Homes, 1951-1959 (Box 24A, Folder 1-3)
    Kykuit gardens; The Eyrie and gardens; Bassett Hall gardens; JY Ranch; Arizona Inn.
  - Photograph Album - Family, Christmas, and Post-1960, 1951-1962 (Box 24A, Folder 4-5)
    Wedding pictures at Rockefeller Center; Rockefeller family Christmas gatherings and other family gatherings; California trip, 1961; JDR, Jr. commemorative plaque at Rockefeller Center, 1962.
  - MBR - JDR, Jr. Wedding, 1951 (Box 29)
    Newspaper clippings.
  - MBR - JDR, Jr. Wedding, 1951 (Box 30)
- Personal Memoranda Books and House Books, 3; 1.23 Cubic Feet 1 legal document box and 2 letter document boxes
  - Art Ready Reference (Box 25, Folder 1)
    Descriptions of 740 apartment.
  - Art Works (Box 25, Folder 2)
    Descriptions of art at 740; AAR distribution results 1958 and 1960; proposed disposition of items not claimed by children.
  - Clothing Lists for Trips, 1954-1963; 2 books. (Box 25, Folder 3)
    Personal needs to be carried on trips.
  - Contributions and Gifts, circa 1951-1970; 2 books. (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Greenrock and Office (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Hillcrest (New House) (Box 25, Folder 6)
    MBR's notes on building and furnishing Hillcrest; record of purchase and payment; description of furnishings; size; problems encountered; sketches.
  - Clothing Lists (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Dr. McCracken and Riverside Church (Box 25, Folder 8)
    MBR gifts to Dr. McCracken and Richard Weagly.
  - Metropolitan Museum and Cloisters, 1961-1965 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    Meetings with Rorimer; information on staff and art works.
  - Miscellaneous Projects and Gifts (Box 25, Folder 10)
    Summaries of gifts to projects and individuals; personal assistance trust.
  - Political - Nelson A. Rockefeller Staff (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Irma, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Scrapbook Diary (Box 25, Folder 13)
    Gifts schedules, made and received; books read; forms for use in letters; medical advice and condition; memberships; magazines; weddings and divorces; thanks.
  - Music, Recordings (Box 25, Folder 14)
    Pianos, music, lists, notes on conductors and performers; radio and TV; records bought and to get.
  - Address Book - New York (Box 25, Folder 15-16)
    Family members; 740 tenants; addresses A-Z with notes.
  - Address Book - Outside New York (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Addresses A-Z outside New York; Red Cross.
  - Social Engagements - New York; Addresses and Social Engagements - Seal Harbor (Box 26, Folder 2)
    Social contacts; thanks; Seal Harbor, Virginia addresses; invitations not accepted.
  - Art Loans (Box 26, Folder 3)
    Policy on refusing loan of art work.
  - Food (Box 26, Folder 4)
    Recipes and menus.
  - Address Book - Providence, Rhode Island (Box 26, Folder 5)
    Social calendar, parties, weddings.
  - Repertoire (Box 26, Folder 6)
    MBR - where and what she played, 1917-.
  - Wine (Box 26, Folder 7)
    MBR's tastes, selections and recommendations.
  - House and Info, Linens; art works; decorations; furnishings for Kykuit; 740 Park Avenue. (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Supplemental Contributions and Gifts (Past) (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - House Books, 6 books. (Box 27)
    Contents of 740 Park Ave.; Hillcrest ("Country"); partial lists for Kykuit, Seal Harbor, and Bassett Hall; AAR distribution lists.
- Room 5600 (Rockefeller family office) File, 4; 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  - Martha Baird Rockefeller General, 1951-1961 (Box 28)
  - Sale of Upton Avenue Property, 1951 (Box 28)
  - Providence Employees, 1951 (Box 28)
  - Publicity, 1952-1953 (Box 28)
    Columnist comment.
  - MBR Boston Symphony Orchestra, 1953-1962 (Box 28)
    MBR support of Symphony and Tanglewood program.
  - Christmas, 1954-1960 (Box 28)
  - MBR Contributions, 1957-1962 (Box 28)
    Special music contributions. Small gifts to local organizations. MBR, DSC.
  - MBR Mary E. Hutt, 1958-1959 (Box 28)
  - MBR Pocantico Hills Property, 1960 (Box 28)
    Purchase of land from Greenrock. Preparations for building home. MBR.
  - MBR Finances and Securities, 1951-1953 (Box 28)
    Liquidation of securities owned before marrige to JDR Jr. MBR.
- Office Files (Mary Packard Files), 5; 2.63 Cubic Feet 2 record storage boxes
  - Office Files (Box 1)
    Office files of MBR's personal secretary.
  - Office Files (Box 2)
- Press Clippings and Annual reports, 7; 2.63 Cubic Feet 2 record storage boxes
  - Press Clippings and Annual Reports (Box 1)
    Press clippings, brochures, pamphlets, maps, and notes on a wide variety of topics of interest to MBR; some annual reports for some of the organizations she supported or was interested in.
  - Press Clippings and Annual Reports (Box 2)
- Piano Music, 8; 2.63 Cubic Feet 2 record storage boxes
  - Piano music (Box 1)
    Bach, Beethoven, Brahms, Chopin. Possibly used by MBR.
  - Piano music (Box 2)
    Debussy, Frank, Handel, Haydn, Lizst, MacDowell, Mozart, Schumann, Saint Saens, Stravinsky; miscellaneous sheet music. Possibly used by MBR.